<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Introduction on Analysing Song Artists and Lyrics Through Genius</title><link>https://davidariostenfeldt.github.io/project_website/</link><description>Recent content in Introduction on Analysing Song Artists and Lyrics Through Genius</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://davidariostenfeldt.github.io/project_website/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data description</title><link>https://davidariostenfeldt.github.io/project_website/data-description/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidariostenfeldt.github.io/project_website/data-description/</guid><description>Gathering the data An impossibly large number of songs have been composed and released throughout the last century. Today songs are being released faster than one person can enjoy them due to the numerous platforms for music streaming such as Spotify. In an attempt to gather music-related data which is both diverse in the number of artists, while focusing on the ones known by most, and also represents as many popular genres as possible, we turned to the Billboard &amp;lsquo;The Hot 100&amp;rsquo; list.</description></item><item><title>Network analysis</title><link>https://davidariostenfeldt.github.io/project_website/network-analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidariostenfeldt.github.io/project_website/network-analysis/</guid><description>This section will cover the collaboration between artists through the use of networks. For this, we will use different network theories and constructions to analyse the properties of artists. Specifically, we will go through how the complete network of all artists was created and investigate it using various networks science analysis strategies. In addition to the network of all artists, we&amp;rsquo;ve also created smaller networks for specific genres. All this, and more, can be seen at the bottom of the page.</description></item><item><title>Text analysis</title><link>https://davidariostenfeldt.github.io/project_website/text-analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidariostenfeldt.github.io/project_website/text-analysis/</guid><description>The lyrics retrieved from Genius.com provide a rich look into the language used in mainstream music throughout the last sixty years. There is a lot to analyse, so the page is divided into three sections. The first section goes over the differences and similarities between genres. Next comes a section exposing the trends of each decade, and lastly, the reader is invited on a deep dive into the linguistic proficiency of the most successful artist in modern times.</description></item></channel></rss>